

Caleb Bertrand

Computer Science Major at University of Louisiana at Lafayette

Profile

I am a web developer and programmer with professional office-setting work in the oilfield. I lived over 7 years in Hong Kong and have also visited Thailand, Romania, and Mexico. Most of this time I spent doing humanitarian volunteer work. As a result, I might be so bold as to say I am "culturally competent".

Aside from computer science, psychology always interested me and I dream of how it could be implemented with AI to enhance education.

Employment History

Data Analyst at Mistras Group, Inc., Lafayette

January 2019 — November 2019

Analyzed inspection data from mechanical integrity technicians to determine their accuracy and identify discrepancies. Entered this information into various databases, and created a report to be sent to the client. During my time here, I automated some of the data entry processes and made suggestions to the IT team which they used to improve one of the said databases. This job required me to meet deadlines and communicate effectively with other data analysts, CAD drawers, and technicians.

Freelance Web Developer

February 2017 — Present

I've worked for 3 years as a freelance web developer and built several sites. Each is responsive and user friendly. I primarily hand-code them, to give clients a truly unique and lightweight product. I have experience with content management systems, several APIs, web hosting, and domains.

On top of the technical work, I work with my clients to help them better define their product or service and what they want the site to accomplish. I guide them on how to present information in an attractive, concise, and organized way.

Here are a couple of my favorite sites:

https://temeculachristianfellowship.com

https://bieltunnelboats.com

Education

High School + Dual Enrollment

GPA: 3.85

ACT: 30

College Credits in Algebra, Chemistry, Philosophy, Civilization, Public Speaking, and History

Courses

User Experience, Linkedin

Cybersecurity, Linkedin

PHP, Linkedin

Node.js, Linkedin

SQL, Linkedin

Social Media Marketing, Linkedin

Contact

3372243404

caleb.a.bertrand@gmail.com

Links

Website:

calebbertrand.github.io

Instagram:

actual_caleb

Skills

Javascript (jQuery, Node, etc)

HTML (Canvas, Etc.)

CSS (SASS)

UX/Design

Y Extra-curricular activities

Javascript Projects

While learning javascript, I built a few projects for fun. These included a maze generator, real-time chat, virtual aquarium, sound visualizer, space invaders recreation, and a program that mapped particles to text in a physics simulation. Here is one of my favorites:

https://soundprogram.herokuapp.com/index.html

Volunteer Work

Churches, Lafayette

Worked as a sound mixer and projectionist, helped with flood relief, and led Bible studies.

YWAM, Hong Kong

January 2020 — June 2020

Helped manage and distribute food, sanitizers and other supplies to the elderly and make masks for distribution to combat the COVID-19 virus.

Sanitized subdivided flat homes using UV light technology.

¶ References

Garey Darce, Mechanical Integrity Data Process Manager from Mistras Group, Inc.

337-354-3042

Vanessa Saldina from YWAM Hong Kong

852-9360-5098